hariharakrishna321@gmail.com



Software Developer

HARIHARA KRISHNA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer with 2+ years in cloud-based SaaS support, resolving technical issues, and enhancing client satisfaction, skilled in JavaScript MERN(MongoDB Express React Node), Java Spring MVC, .NET MVC, AWS, and DevOps tools (Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins), seeking Software Developer roles to contribute expertise.

hariharakrishna1

in hariharakrishna-v

EDUCATION

2024 - Now

Master of Science (MS)

Nottingham Trent University / United Kingdom, Nottingham

Developed scripts to fortify the security in Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) Communication using a customised Hybrid Blockchain.

2018 - 2022

Bachelor of Science (BS)

Anna University / India, Chennai Secured placement with Mphasis Ltd demonstrating strong software development skills

SKILLS

JavaScript MERN Experienced Backend Development Experienced ASP.NET MVC Experienced Java Spring MVC Experienced Angular Experienced Skillful PHP Laravel Agile Methodologies Skillful **Unit Testing** Experienced

EXPERIENCE

2020 - 2023

Software Developer Mphasis / India, Hyderabad

Designed and maintained scalable back-end services using emerging technologies such as Typescript, Spring Boot, Hibernate, MySQL Database Management System, Angular, AWS, and DockerHub, optimizing performance by 35% for an E-Medicare web application.

Self-Motivated approach in adapting to Laravel and MERN based back-end and front-end development within an impromptu short term to juggle multiple projects simultaneously.

Directed a group of software developers to achieve deadline(s) in prior to release date with the help of Git version control and effective debugging.

Played a steadfast role in an Agile/Scrum team at Mphasis Ltd, committing to a 20% increase in productivity in software development lifecycle.

Enhanced CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins, Docker, and other software development tools, ensuring seamless integration and delivery of microservices on AWS.

INTERNSHIPS

2020 - 2020

Cyber Security Intern Verzeo / India, Chennai

Developed, tested and deployed security policies for all aspect of computer and network security based on ISO 27001 Certification model.

Adopted security techniques in modern development frameworks such as Express.js, React.js, Node.js and Vue.js.

Demonstrated application and infrastructure penetration tests, as well as physical security review and social engineering tests for global clients.

Identified potential risks early in the software development cycle, leading to a 10% decrease in project delays.